<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>

  <!-- ===========================
       CLASS: THE INVESTED
       =========================== -->
  <element name="Invested" type="Class" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_INVESTED">
    <description>
      <p><strong>Masters of the Metallic Arts</strong></p>
      <p><em>“Power is the soul made manifest — and the metal that binds it.”</em></p>

      <p>
        The Invested are mortals who manipulate the invisible threads of spirit through metal.
        By burning metals, storing essence, or forging soul-spikes, they command reality through
        the mysterious power of Investiture. Whether noble scion or haunted killer, the Invested
        bridges the gap between mortal and divine through raw spiritual will.
      </p>

      <h4>Hit Points</h4>
      <ul>
        <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per Invested level</li>
        <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
        <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per Invested level after 1st</li>
      </ul>

      <h4>Proficiencies</h4>
      <ul>
        <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
        <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
        <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Smith’s tools</li>
        <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Wisdom</li>
        <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, or Survival.</li>
      </ul>

      <h4>Primary Abilities</h4>
      <p>Constitution, Wisdom</p>

      <h4>Metal Dice</h4>
      <p>
        At the heart of your abilities lies a pool of <strong>Metal Dice</strong> — representations of the metals you channel
        and the spirit that fuels them.
      </p>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><th>Level</th><th>Metal Dice</th><th>Die Size</th><th>Notes</th></tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr><td>1–4</td><td>2</td><td>d6</td><td>Fuel for subclass powers</td></tr>
          <tr><td>5–10</td><td>3</td><td>d8</td><td>Increased potency</td></tr>
          <tr><td>11–16</td><td>4</td><td>d10</td><td>Enhanced strength</td></tr>
          <tr><td>17–20</td><td>5</td><td>d12</td><td>Peak Investiture</td></tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <p><strong>Using Metal Dice.</strong> When a class or subclass feature calls for a Metal Die, roll one and apply the result as damage, healing, or power level as described.</p>
      <p><strong>Recharging.</strong> You regain all expended Metal Dice when you finish a long rest. At 18th level (Sublime Flow), you regain half your expended Metal Dice when you finish a short rest.</p>
      <p><strong>Augmentation.</strong> Once per turn, you can add a Metal Die to a damage roll, ability check, or saving throw.</p>

      <h4>Class Features by Level</h4>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><th>Level</th><th>Features</th></tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr><td>1</td><td>Metallic Connection, Metal Dice</td></tr>
          <tr><td>2</td><td>Metal Sense</td></tr>
          <tr><td>3</td><td>Path Feature, Refined Technique</td></tr>
          <tr><td>4</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
          <tr><td>5</td><td>Path Feature</td></tr>
          <tr><td>6</td><td>Extra Metal Die (3 total)</td></tr>
          <tr><td>7</td><td>Path Feature</td></tr>
          <tr><td>8</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
          <tr><td>9</td><td>Path Feature</td></tr>
          <tr><td>10</td><td>Metal Resilience</td></tr>
          <tr><td>11</td><td>Quick Burn</td></tr>
          <tr><td>12</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
          <tr><td>13</td><td>Path Feature</td></tr>
          <tr><td>14</td><td>Path Capstone</td></tr>
          <tr><td>15</td><td>Dual Manipulation</td></tr>
          <tr><td>16</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
          <tr><td>17</td><td>Master of Metals</td></tr>
          <tr><td>18</td><td>Sublime Flow</td></tr>
          <tr><td>19</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
          <tr><td>20</td><td>Ascendant Being</td></tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <h4>Metallic Arts Summary</h4>
      <p><strong>Allomantic Metals:</strong> Iron (Pull), Steel (Push), Pewter (Strength), Tin (Senses), Brass (Soothe), Zinc (Riot), Bronze (Seek), Copper (Hide), Gold (Heal), Electrum (Future Glimpse)</p>
      <p><strong>Feruchemical Attributes:</strong> Strength, Health, Speed, Perception, Stamina, Weight</p>
      <p><strong>Hemalurgic Spikes:</strong> Bestial, Arcane, Resilient, Divine, Mental</p>
    </description>

    <!-- Simple sheet blurb -->
    <sheet>
      <description>A mortal who channels spiritual power through metal, choosing a Path of Allomancy, Feruchemy, or Hemalurgy.</description>
    </sheet>

    <!-- NOTE: Aurora's official data also encodes hit die, proficiencies, etc. in rules/stats.
         To keep this portable, this class relies mostly on description text.
         You can copy how Cleric/Fighter do it in the official XML and mirror that here. -->
  </element>

  <!-- ===========================
       CORE CLASS FEATURES
       =========================== -->

  <!-- 1st: Metallic Connection + Metal Dice -->
  <element name="Metallic Connection" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_METALLIC_CONNECTION">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Metallic Connection</strong></p>
      <p><em>1st-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You awaken your soul’s link to the Metallic Arts and choose a <strong>Path</strong>:
        Allomancy, Feruchemy, or Hemalurgy. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again
        at 3rd, 5th, 7th, 9th, 13th, and 14th levels.
      </p>
      <p>
        Your mastery of metal also grants you a pool of <strong>Metal Dice</strong>, which fuel many of your
        abilities. At 1st level, you have two Metal Dice, which are d6s. You expend Metal Dice to
        power class and subclass features.
      </p>
      <p>
        When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended Metal Dice. Starting at 18th level
        (Sublime Flow), you also regain half of your expended Metal Dice when you finish a short rest.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Augmentation.</strong> Once per turn, when you make a damage roll, ability check, or saving throw,
        you can roll one of your Metal Dice and add the result to the roll.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 2nd: Metal Sense -->
  <element name="Metal Sense" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_METAL_SENSE">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Metal Sense</strong></p>
      <p><em>2nd-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Your soul resonates with nearby metal. You can detect the presence of metal within 30 feet of you,
        even if it is behind total cover, though not its precise shape. You also sense the presence of
        Invested or magical creatures or objects within this range, though not their exact identity.
      </p>
      <p>
        You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks to locate hidden metals, metallic
        mechanisms, or constructs.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 3rd: Refined Technique -->
  <element name="Refined Technique" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_REFINED_TECHNIQUE">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Refined Technique</strong></p>
      <p><em>3rd-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You learn to streamline your metalworking of the soul. Once per short or long rest, you can use
        one <strong>minor subclass ability</strong> that normally takes an action as a bonus action instead.
        (Your DM determines which features of your chosen Path count as “minor” for this purpose, but
        generally shorter-duration, single-target, or utility effects qualify.)
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 6th: Extra Metal Die (scaling note) -->
  <element name="Extra Metal Die" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_EXTRA_METAL_DIE">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Extra Metal Die</strong></p>
      <p><em>6th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Your reserves deepen. At 6th level, your pool of Metal Dice increases to <strong>3 dice</strong>, and
        their size becomes <strong>d8</strong>. This matches the Metal Dice table in the class description.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 10th: Metal Resilience -->
  <element name="Metal Resilience" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_METAL_RESILIENCE">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Metal Resilience</strong></p>
      <p><em>10th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Your soul flows more readily through your metal reserves. When you roll initiative, you regain
        1 expended Metal Die.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 11th: Quick Burn -->
  <element name="Quick Burn" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_QUICK_BURN">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Quick Burn</strong></p>
      <p><em>11th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can flare metals with remarkable speed. Once on each of your turns, you can use a subclass
        ability that normally requires an action as a bonus action instead.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 15th: Dual Manipulation -->
  <element name="Dual Manipulation" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_DUAL_MANIPULATION">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Dual Manipulation</strong></p>
      <p><em>15th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can split your focus between multiple streams of power. On your turn, you can use
        <strong>two different metal-based abilities</strong>, as long as they come from different sources
        (such as different metals or attributes) and obey the normal action economy. For example, you might
        burn Steel and Pewter in the same turn, or Tap Speed and Strength at once.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 17th: Master of Metals -->
  <element name="Master of Metals" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_MASTER_OF_METALS">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Master of Metals</strong></p>
      <p><em>17th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You have studied the Metallic Arts beyond the bounds of your own discipline. Choose one feature
        from another <strong>Path of the Invested</strong> (Allomancer, Feruchemist, or Hemalurgist)
        that is gained at 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, 9th, or 13th level in that Path. You gain that feature,
        using your Invested level in place of that Path’s level when needed.
      </p>
      <p>
        You count as a member of that Path solely for the purpose of using this feature.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 18th: Sublime Flow -->
  <element name="Sublime Flow" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_SUBLIME_FLOW">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Sublime Flow</strong></p>
      <p><em>18th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Your spirit and metals cycle in a constant rhythm. When you finish a short rest, you regain
        Metal Dice equal to <strong>half</strong> the number you have expended (rounded down).
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- 20th: Ascendant Being -->
  <element name="Ascendant Being" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_CLASS_FEATURE_INVESTED_ASCENDANT_BEING">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Ascendant Being</strong></p>
      <p><em>20th-level Invested feature</em></p>
      <p>
        For a brief time, your body radiates pure Investiture and you stand on the edge of divinity.
        As an action, you can enter an ascendant state that lasts for 1 minute. For the duration:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>You treat your Metal Dice as <strong>unlimited</strong>; you can expend them without tracking uses.</li>
        <li>You have advantage on all saving throws.</li>
        <li>You have resistance to all damage types.</li>
        <li>Your weapon attacks and offensive abilities deal radiant or necrotic damage (your choice) instead of their normal type.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- ===========================
       PATHS OF THE INVESTED
       Implemented as Archetypes
       =========================== -->

  <!-- ===== PATH OF THE ALLOMANCER ===== -->
  <element name="Path of the Allomancer" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_INVESTED_ALLOMANCER">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Path of the Allomancer</strong></p>
      <p><em>“I am the storm that bends iron and wills men.”</em></p>
      <p>
        Allomancers consume and “burn” trace metals within their bodies to unleash bursts of spiritual power.
        Iron and Steel push and pull, Pewter hardens flesh, and subtle metals twist emotions and obscure
        detection. An Allomancer fights as a living engine of flaring metal and will.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Allomancer 1: Burn Metals -->
  <element name="Burn Metals" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_ALLOMANCER_BURN_METALS">
    <supports>Path of the Allomancer</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Burn Metals</strong></p>
      <p><em>1st-level Path of the Allomancer feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can burn specific metals by expending a Metal Die to produce one of the following effects.
        Unless otherwise noted, each effect lasts until the start of your next turn.
      </p>

      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><th>Metal</th><th>Effect</th></tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Iron</strong></td>
            <td>
              <strong>Pull.</strong> As an action, choose a metallic object or a creature wearing/carrying metal
              within 30 feet. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier)
              or be pulled up to 10 feet toward you, plus 5 feet for each Metal Die expended.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Steel</strong></td>
            <td>
              <strong>Push.</strong> As an action, choose an object or creature within 30 feet. The target must succeed
              on a Strength saving throw or be shoved 10 feet away from you, plus 5 feet per Metal Die spent. Alternatively,
              you can propel yourself, increasing your jump distance and ignoring difficult terrain until the end of your turn.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Pewter</strong></td>
            <td>
              You gain a +2 bonus to Strength checks, and you gain temporary hit points equal to the result of your Metal Die
              + your Constitution modifier. These benefits last for 1 minute.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Tin</strong></td>
            <td>
              For 1 minute, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks, and you can see
              in dim light as if it were bright light.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Brass</strong></td>
            <td>
              As an action, you soothe a creature’s emotions (as the <em>calm emotions</em> spell) within 30 feet.
              The target must make a Charisma saving throw against your Invested save DC (8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier).
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Zinc</strong></td>
            <td>
              As an action, you incite a creature within 30 feet to hostility. On a failed Wisdom saving throw, the target must
              use its reaction (if available) to make one melee attack against a creature of your choice.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Bronze</strong></td>
            <td>
              You sense Invested or magical effects within 30 feet of you until the end of your next turn, learning their general
              direction and school or nature of power, if any.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Copper</strong></td>
            <td>
              For 1 minute, you and creatures of your choice within 10 feet of you are veiled from divination and detection effects,
              as if affected by <em>nondetection</em>.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Gold</strong></td>
            <td>
              You regain hit points equal to the result of your Metal Die + your Wisdom modifier.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Electrum</strong></td>
            <td>
              The next time you make an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw within 1 minute, roll 2d20 and choose either result.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Allomancer 5: Duralumin Flare -->
  <element name="Duralumin Flare" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_ALLOMANCER_DURALUMIN_FLARE">
    <supports>Path of the Allomancer</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Duralumin Flare</strong></p>
      <p><em>5th-level Path of the Allomancer feature</em></p>
      <p>
        When you burn a metal using a Metal Die, you can expend an <strong>additional</strong> Metal Die to flare it with
        duralumin. The metal’s range, potency, or duration (your choice) is doubled. For example, you might double Steel’s
        shove distance, Tin’s duration, or the temporary hit points granted by Pewter.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Allomancer 9: Precision Push/Pull -->
  <element name="Precision Push/Pull" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_ALLOMANCER_PRECISION">
    <supports>Path of the Allomancer</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Precision Push/Pull</strong></p>
      <p><em>9th-level Path of the Allomancer feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can apply force to even small or non-metallic objects. While burning Iron or Steel, you can Push or Pull
        non-metallic objects up to 20 pounds within 30 feet and manipulate them with fine precision, such as opening
        latches, drawing weapons, or moving keys and small items.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Allomancer 13: Steelrunner -->
  <element name="Steelrunner" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_ALLOMANCER_STEELRUNNER">
    <supports>Path of the Allomancer</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Steelrunner</strong></p>
      <p><em>13th-level Path of the Allomancer feature</em></p>
      <p>
        While you are burning Steel or Pewter, your speed increases by 20 feet, and you can take the Dash action as a
        bonus action on each of your turns for up to 1 minute.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Allomancer 14: Mistborn Ascendant -->
  <element name="Mistborn Ascendant" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_ALLOMANCER_MISTBORN_ASCENDANT">
    <supports>Path of the Allomancer</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Mistborn Ascendant</strong></p>
      <p><em>14th-level Path of the Allomancer feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Once per long rest, you can burn all metals in a storm of power. As a bonus action, you enter a Mistborn state
        for 1 minute. For the duration:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>You can use <strong>two metal powers per turn</strong>.</li>
        <li>You have advantage on all saving throws.</li>
        <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== PATH OF THE FERUCHEMIST ===== -->
  <element name="Path of the Feruchemist" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_INVESTED_FERUCHEMIST">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Path of the Feruchemist</strong></p>
      <p><em>“I store what I am so I may become what I must.”</em></p>
      <p>
        Feruchemists store their own essence within metalminds, drawing upon it later to amplify themselves.
        They pay a price now to gain incredible power in the moments that matter.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Feruchemist 1: Store and Tap -->
  <element name="Store and Tap" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_FERUCHEMIST_STORE_TAP">
    <supports>Path of the Feruchemist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Store and Tap</strong></p>
      <p><em>1st-level Path of the Feruchemist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can store or tap one of the following attributes in a metalmind you carry:
        <strong>Strength, Health, Speed, Perception, Stamina, or Weight</strong>.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Store.</strong> For each hour you store an attribute, you take a –2 penalty to checks and rolls that
        rely on that attribute (as decided by the DM). The stored power accumulates in your metalmind.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>Tap.</strong> As a bonus action, you can Tap one stored attribute, expending a Metal Die. For a number
        of minutes equal to your Invested level, you gain a +2 bonus on rolls using that attribute (such as Strength checks,
        Constitution saving throws for Stamina, or Wisdom (Perception) checks for Perception).
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Feruchemist 5: Doublemind Storage -->
  <element name="Doublemind Storage" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_FERUCHEMIST_DOUBLEMIND">
    <supports>Path of the Feruchemist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Doublemind Storage</strong></p>
      <p><em>5th-level Path of the Feruchemist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can store or tap <strong>two attributes at once</strong>. When you do so, each attribute functions as it
        normally would for Store and Tap, but you must track each separately.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Feruchemist 9: Compound Reserves -->
  <element name="Compound Reserves" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_FERUCHEMIST_COMPOUND_RESERVES">
    <supports>Path of the Feruchemist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Compound Reserves</strong></p>
      <p><em>9th-level Path of the Feruchemist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        When you expend a Metal Die to Tap an attribute, roll the die twice and choose the higher result to determine any
        effect that scales with the die’s roll (such as bonus hit points or bonus movement if your DM uses such scaling).
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Feruchemist 13: Feruchemical Flow -->
  <element name="Feruchemical Flow" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_FERUCHEMIST_FLOW">
    <supports>Path of the Feruchemist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Feruchemical Flow</strong></p>
      <p><em>13th-level Path of the Feruchemist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can begin storing an attribute as a bonus action instead of needing extended downtime. You can maintain
        this focused storage for up to 10 minutes, suffering the normal penalties while rapidly filling your metalminds.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Feruchemist 14: Fullborn Surge -->
  <element name="Fullborn Surge" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_FERUCHEMIST_FULLBORN_SURGE">
    <supports>Path of the Feruchemist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Fullborn Surge</strong></p>
      <p><em>14th-level Path of the Feruchemist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Once per long rest, you may unleash all your stored attributes at once. As a bonus action, you Tap all attributes
        you currently have stored for 1 minute. For the duration:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>You gain a +2 bonus on all rolls.</li>
        <li>At the start of each of your turns, you regain 10 hit points.</li>
        <li>You have resistance to all damage except psychic.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== PATH OF THE HEMALURGIST ===== -->
  <element name="Path of the Hemalurgist" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_INVESTED_HEMALURGIST">
    <supports>Invested</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Path of the Hemalurgist</strong></p>
      <p><em>“Through death, I claim power.”</em></p>
      <p>
        Hemalurgists steal fragments of souls, embedding them as spikes. Each spike grants great power — and greater
        damnation. Their bodies and minds warp under the weight of stolen Investiture, tracked by a Corruption score.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Hemalurgist 1: Hemalurgic Craft -->
  <element name="Hemalurgic Craft" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_HEMALURGIST_CRAFT">
    <supports>Path of the Hemalurgist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Hemalurgic Craft</strong></p>
      <p><em>1st-level Path of the Hemalurgist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can forge soul-spikes from the dead. When a creature dies within 10 feet of you, you can spend 1 hour
        working with a suitable piece of metal to craft a <strong>Hemalurgic spike</strong> from the creature’s remains.
      </p>
      <p>
        Each spike grants you one trait from the creature and increases your <strong>Corruption</strong> by 1.
        Your maximum number of spikes equals your proficiency bonus. If you ever exceed this limit, you must immediately
        choose and destroy spikes until you are at or below the maximum.
      </p>

      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><th>Spike Type</th><th>Benefit</th></tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Bestial</strong></td>
            <td>You gain a +2 bonus to Strength <em>or</em> Dexterity (your choice when the spike is created).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Arcane</strong></td>
            <td>You learn one 1st-level spell from the creature’s spell list. You can cast it once per long rest without a spell slot, using Wisdom as your casting ability.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Resilient</strong></td>
            <td>You gain a +1 bonus to AC <em>or</em> resistance to one damage type the creature could resist.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Divine</strong></td>
            <td>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you regain hit points equal to your proficiency bonus.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><strong>Mental</strong></td>
            <td>You have advantage on Wisdom <em>or</em> Intelligence checks (choose one when the spike is created).</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>

      <p>
        Your <strong>Corruption</strong> score is equal to the number of spikes you currently bear. The DM may call
        for additional roleplay or drawbacks as your Corruption grows.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Hemalurgist 5: Blood for Power -->
  <element name="Blood for Power" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_HEMALURGIST_BLOOD_FOR_POWER">
    <supports>Path of the Hemalurgist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Blood for Power</strong></p>
      <p><em>5th-level Path of the Hemalurgist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can trade your own life for fuel. As a bonus action, you can take damage equal to your proficiency bonus
        to regain one expended Metal Die.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Hemalurgist 9: Hybrid Spikes -->
  <element name="Hybrid Spikes" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_HEMALURGIST_HYBRID_SPIKES">
    <supports>Path of the Hemalurgist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Hybrid Spikes</strong></p>
      <p><em>9th-level Path of the Hemalurgist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You can merge the powers of your spikes. When crafting a spike, you can combine two spike traits into one
        hybrid spike. This hybrid spike counts as <strong>2 Corruption</strong> and uses up two of your spike slots,
        but grants both chosen benefits.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Hemalurgist 13: Controlled Madness -->
  <element name="Controlled Madness" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_HEMALURGIST_CONTROLLED_MADNESS">
    <supports>Path of the Hemalurgist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Controlled Madness</strong></p>
      <p><em>13th-level Path of the Hemalurgist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        You ride the edge of sanity without falling. You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed,
        frightened, or magically dominated. In addition, you add your current <strong>Corruption</strong> score to
        all Charisma (Intimidation) checks.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <!-- Hemalurgist 14: Godblood Ascendant -->
  <element name="Godblood Ascendant" type="Class Feature" source="Homebrew" id="ID_FEATURE_INVESTED_HEMALURGIST_GODBLOOD_ASCENDANT">
    <supports>Path of the Hemalurgist</supports>
    <description>
      <p><strong>Godblood Ascendant</strong></p>
      <p><em>14th-level Path of the Hemalurgist feature</em></p>
      <p>
        Once per long rest, you can fully embrace your corruption. As a bonus action, you enter a Godblood state
        for 1 minute. For the duration:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>You have resistance to all damage.</li>
        <li>You can use any Path of the Invested ability, regardless of which Path you chose.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        When the state ends, you take 4d12 necrotic damage that can’t be reduced in any way, and your
        <strong>Corruption</strong> score increases by 1 permanently.
      </p>
    </description>
  </element>

</elements>
